<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | Visual Computing Lab</title><link>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/</link><atom:link href="http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 10:39:08 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>ECHOES</title><link>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/echoes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 10:39:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/echoes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reflex</title><link>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/reflex/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 10:39:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/reflex/</guid><description>&lt;p>REFLectance EXploration research project aims to improve the entire workflow stemming from multi-light image collections
(sets of photographs captured with a fixed camera but variable illumination) for surface characterization and analysis. &lt;br>
PRIN 2022 2022E2ANE9&lt;br>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ATRIUM</title><link>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/atrium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/atrium/</guid><description>&lt;h3>Full project name:&lt;/h3>
ATRIUM - Advancing FronTier Research In the Arts and hUManities
&lt;h3>Duration:&lt;/h3>
48 months, January 2024 to December 2027
&lt;h3>Project coordinator:&lt;/h3>
Digital Research Infrastructure for the Arts and Humanities (DARIAH)
&lt;h3>Consortium:&lt;/h3>
The ATRIUM Consortium is structured around 4 core Research Infrastructures (DARIAH, ARIADNE, CLARIN and OPERAS) with 29 partners (including 12 affiliated entities) from 14 different countries: Austria (OEAW), Belgium (ARIADNE and OPERAS), Cyprus (CYI), the Czech Republic (ARUB, ARUP and CU), Germany (LMU MUENCHEN), France (DARIAH, FOXCUB, INRIA, TOURS), Greece (ATHENA-RC, AUEB, FORTH), Italy (CNR, NET7, PIN, PRISMA), The Netherlands (CLARIN, RADBOUD), Poland (IBL PAN, PSNC), Portugal (LNEC), Serbia (BCDH), Sweden (SND) and the United Kingdom (UoY_ADS, USFD, USW).
&lt;h3>Summary of main topic and goals:&lt;/h3>
ATRIUM aims to empower Arts and Humanities scholars in their use of digital methods by facilitating access to a wide range of reusable workflows and interoperable, composable services offered by leading research infrastructures in the Arts and Humanities domain.
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Topic-ID: HORIZON-INFRA-2023-SERV-01-02&lt;/br>
Call-ID: HORIZON-INFRA-2023-SERV-01&lt;/br>
Type of action: HORIZON-RIA&lt;/br>
Grant Agreement number: 101132163&lt;/br>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Charity</title><link>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/charity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 10:39:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/charity/</guid><description>&lt;p>ENergy aware BIM Cloud Platform in a COst-effective Building REnovation Context&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2018-2021 EC H2020-NMBP-EEB-2018&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Encore</title><link>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/encore/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 10:39:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/encore/</guid><description>&lt;p>ENergy aware BIM Cloud Platform in a COst-effective Building REnovation Context&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2018-2021 EC H2020-NMBP-EEB-2018&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Evocation</title><link>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/evocation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 10:39:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/evocation/</guid><description>&lt;p>2018-2022 H2020-MSCA-ITN-2018 Innovative Training Networks (ITN)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PNRR CHANGES</title><link>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/changes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/changes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>OPUS</title><link>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/opus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/opus/</guid><description>&lt;h3>OPUS - Open AI solutions for historical masonry annotation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Understanding historical masonries in cultural heritage assets is a challenging task that involves different disciplinary fields and the work of experts.&lt;/br>
The annotation of historical masonry is a process of association between the graphically represented element and any relevant knowledge-based information. This autoptic analysis is vital for supporting the documentation, analysis and diagnosis of heritage structures. The conventional approach is based on the manual drawing of annotated regions over photos or orthographic images of the structure. This makes the process prohibitively time consuming and extremely costly, limiting the ability to manage large-scale monitoring.&lt;/br>
The OPUS project aims to develop and test an integrated AI-based system for the assisted and automatic annotation of historical masonries. The project will tackle the annotation task using both assisted AI-based tools and automated CNN (Convolutional Neural Networks) semantic segmentation models, working at different levels and granularity: the mapping of construction features, namely techniques and materials, and the mapping of individual constituent elements.&lt;/br>
The aim will be reached through the use of TagLab, an open-source AI-powered semantic segmentation software developed by the project&amp;rsquo;s partners. This tool, originally designed to work on marine biology, will be extended to work on masonries and improved by tweaking and extending its functionalities. A key part of the project’s approach is to maintain the role of the expert pivotal. Our aim is not to create a novel process of masonry annotation, but to complement the current workflow with AI technology, able to support and facilitate the manual annotation, and to automate the large-scale tasks.&lt;/br>
The project will work on the theoretical aspects of the masonry annotation, formalizing the annotation process and mapping to an AI framework, defining the classes of interest and input data, and establishing integrated human-AI annotation workflows. From a methodological viewpoint, the project will promote a transdisciplinary approach to the study of historical masonry. From a technical viewpoint, the project will explore the use of AI technology in the cultural heritage field, developing practical solutions to open research issues: advanced user interface and interaction, use of multi-band data, improving the learning process on real-world data.&lt;/br>
The OPUS project will adopt a case study research approach, as it can generate an in-depth, multi-faceted understanding of masonries located in a geographical area, while mitigating challenges and complexities derived from the variety of local building cultures. The project will reach out to the community working on historical masonry (academic, public and private), distributing the produced datasets as open-data and the developed software as open source, organizing training workshops and dissemination events.&lt;/br>&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
Bando PRIN 2022 Decreto Direttoriale n. 104 del 02-02-2022&lt;/br>
Principal Investigator: Marco Callieri&lt;/br>
Codice progetto: 202277KJ8F&lt;/br>
Settore ERC: SH6&lt;/br>
Durata: 24 mesi&lt;/br></description></item><item><title>PNNR H2IOSC</title><link>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/h2iosc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/h2iosc/</guid><description>&lt;p>h2iosc&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>PNNR MICS</title><link>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/mics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/mics/</guid><description>&lt;p>ENergy aware BIM Cloud Platform in a COst-effective Building REnovation Context&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2018-2021 EC H2020-NMBP-EEB-2018&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SUN-XR</title><link>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/sun/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://vcg.isti.cnr.it/project/sun/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>